Finding Aid for Noble Travis papers, 1927-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Noble Travis papers 1927-1970
Travis, Noble, 1901-
1 linear foot
85491 Aa 2
Detroit, Michigan, banker, state Republican party worker, leader of the Wayne County, Michigan, Republican Precinct Organization; correspondence and topical files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Noble Travis (donor no. 5927 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Noble Travis, a graduate of the University of Michigan Law School, was a Detroit banker and an active member of the state and Wayne County Republican party.
The Noble Travis collection includes correspondence and subject files relating to his political and civic interests. Included are materials on his work with the Detroit Board of Trade and with the Wayne County Republican Precinct Organization. The files also document his interest in Republican politics, especially in the elections of 1942 and 1944, and his work in opposition to Frank McKay's control of the Michigan Republican Party.
Subjects:
Aeronautics.; Detroit Chamber of Commerce.; Elections--Michigan--1942.; Elections--Michigan--1944.; McKay, Frank D., 1883-; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Republican Party (Mich.). Wayne County Republican Precinct Organization.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
- Personal
  - Personal newspapers (Box 1)
  - Travis family papers (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - 1935-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - January-October 1942 (Box 1)
  - November-December 1942 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1943 (Box 1)
  - July 1943 (Box 1)
  - August-December 1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946-1970 (Box 1)
- Topical files
  - Detroit Board of Commerce
    - General, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - Aircraft survey of the Detroit area, 1927, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Hess Aircraft Company, Wyandotte, Michigan, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - Alfred Connable campaign for University of Michigan regent, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Senatorial candidacy of Homer Ferguson, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Election of 1944 (Box 1)
  - Political luncheon for Detroit mayor Edward J. Jeffries, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Wayne County Republican Precinct Organization
    - General, 1944 (Box 1)
    - Newsletter "The Rail-Splitter" 1944 (Box 1)
  - Opposition to Frank McKay, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous political papers (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)